Uchechi OBEME

Junior Civil Engineer || Junior Construction/Project Manager

+234 8067907142 || <u>obemeuchechi@gmail.com</u> || Port Harcourt, Rivers State, Nigeria. https://www.linkedin.com/in/uchechi-obeme/ || Willing to Relocate/Travel — YES

CAREER SUMMARY

A reliable Junior Civil Engineer with 2 years' of work experience in road/building construction project. Skilled in ProtaStructures, Plan Interpretations, and Project Management as well as Project Execution. Able to work independently and collaborate with others in a team to meet organizational set goals.

TRAINING/CERTIFICATIONS

•	lealth, Safety and Environment (HSE 1, 2 & 3), UKSHE Organisation, British ISO. nvironmental Impact Assessment, Department of Petroleum Resources. lational Youth Service Corps (NYSC), Akwa Ibom State, Nigeria. Quality Management, Rahn Wesley Institute of Management.	2019 2019 2019 2019 2019
•	asic First Aid and CPR Training, Novelle Center – Online,	2019 2015
•	lational Youth Service Corps (NYSC), Akwa Ibom State, Nigeria. Quality Management, Rahn Wesley Institute of Management. asic First Aid and CPR Training, Novelle Center – Online,	20 20 20

SKILLS/COMPETENCIES

- **Highly Organized**: It allows me to keep appointments, records, and necessary details in order.
- **Detailed Oriented:** To ensure getting every vital/relevant information in my deliverable and KPIs.
- **Effective Teamwork:** Helps me to listen, pay attention to details, and ably collaborate with others.
- Critical & Analytical: To ably criticize & analyse situations or work and make the best out of them.
- Leadership Capability: To lead by example, manage, and influence people to achieve a goal.
- **Effective Communications:** Helps me to truly relate with diverse people and fellow professionals.
- IT/Microsoft Office Packages: Enables me to be technologically inclined & deliver tasks at ease
- Decision Making/Negotiation: Enables me to make good decisions based on available data.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Site Engineer, ALEED CONSTRUCTION LIMITED, Port Harcourt.

Oct - Nov 2020

Accomplishments

- Supervised iron benders' project, reduced debt profile and boosted revenue by 70% in 3 months
- Attained the highest daily report submission ratings (as determined by external auditors) earned 100% marks in all categories including ongoing project and executed project reports.

Asst. Site Engr, MODERN DUPLEX, SHOP/SECURITY APARTMENT CONSTRUCTIONS. Jan – Jun 2020 Accomplishments

- Participated in the setting out of the site following the drawings and specification.
- Resolved technical issues with employer's reps, supplier, subcontractors and statutory authorities
- Managed the day-to-day site operations, and monitored labour force and subcontractors.
- Calculated quantity of materials used & ensured all operations were as per specifications.
- Supervised the interior furnishing of the entire apartment until 100% completion and handover.

Junior QC Assistant, HENSEK INTEGRATED SERVICES LIMITED, Uyo.

Mar - Oct 2019

Accomplishments

- Effectively assisted in performing tests on soil samples to best determine its construction layer.
- Participated in the setting out of the site following the drawings and specification.
- Performed tests on the concrete mix to achieve quality construction as required in the drawings.
- Conducted site surveillance to ensure works on site are moving as per drawing/specification.
- Assisted in collating database analysis and preparing reports on laboratory test results.

Junior Site Engineer, HENSEK INTEGRATED SERVICES LIMITED, Uyo.

Jan - Feb 2019

- **Accomplishments**
- Effectively participated in the dualization project of a 9.5km road.
- Assisted to carry out supervision of the installation of precast underground drains and side drains.
- Participated to carry out supervision of the filling of construction materials in its different layers.

Civil Engineer Trainee, MINISTRY OF WORKS, Uyo.

Nov 2018 - Oct 2019

Accomplishments

- Assisted and adequately participated in the dualization project of a 9.5km road by HISL.
- Helped to carry out supervision of the installation of precast underground drains and side drains.
- Submitted weekly reports on the progress of on-going work.

Civil Engineer Trainee, HORETH ENGINEERING LIMITED, Port Harcourt

Sept - Oct 2018

- **Accomplishments**
- Participated in the construction of a Containerised Sewage Treatment Plant at Golf Estate
- Assisted in the supervision of the construction of the Rivers State Judiciary Courtrooms.
- Helped in collating database analysis and preparing reports for ongoing projects.

Intern, MONIER CONSTRUCTION COMPANY (MCC) LTD, Port Harcourt.

Aug 2016 - Jan 2017

- **Accomplishments**
- Assisted in supervising the rehabilitation of a 6.13km road as a student site engineer.
- Assisted in supervising the construction of a 0.9m*0.75m drain cast in-situ.
- Prepared daily reports on the progress of work on site.

EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATION

University of Port Harcourt, Choba, Rivers State, Nigeria. **B.Eng. Civil Engineering**

2012 - 2018

Second Class Honours (Upper Division) - 4.2/5.0 CGPA

Niger Delta Science School, Port Harcourt, Rivers State, Nigeria. West African Senior School Certificate Examinations (WASSCE)

2008 - 2010

LEADERSHIP ROLES

Asst. Presiding Officer (APO 1), Nigerian General Elections, Uyo, Akwa Ibom State.

2019

Public Relations Officer (PRO), FYCA, Faculty of Engineering, UNIPORT.

2018

Available on Request. REFEREES: